Guide to the Yale Peruvian Expedition Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
The Yale University-National Geographic Society Peruvian Expedition of 1914-1915 was undertaken in two stages. Between April and November, 1914, the region near Machu Picchu was mapped, some ruins visited in 1911 were surveyed, and an old Inca road leading toward Machu Picchu was discovered. The 1914 staff included Albert H. Bumstead, topographical engineer; Ellwood C. Erdis, chief engineer; Edwin A. Meserve, surgeon; Edwin L. Anderson and C. Frederick Westerberg, assistant topographers; Osgood Hardy, interpreter and chief assistant; and assistant Philip Ainsworth Means, a Harvard student who later became a prominent historian, explorer, and author. Bingham returned to Peru in 1915 as director of the expedition. Anderson, Hardy and Erdis remained in Peru from the 1914 staff. New members of the expedition for 1915 included: botanist Orator F. Cook and assistant botanist G. Bruce Gilbert, both from the Bureau of Plant Industry of the U. S. Department of Agriculture; Edmund Heller, veteran of expeditions to East Africa, Mexico, Guatemala and elsewhere, as naturalist; Clarence F. Maynard, topographer; Dr. David E. Ford, surgeon; Joseph J. Hasbrouck, engineer; Geoffrey W. Morkill, assistant in charge of headquarters; and Ricardo Charaja, assistant to the director.
The principal objective of the 1915 expedition was to secure information about the former inhabitants of Machu Picchu and the nearby region. In the course of exploring Inca roads near Machu Picchu, more ruins were discovered and examined, revealing that the mountain citadel had been the center of a densely populated region. Examination of burial caves and other parts of the Inca ruins yielded numerous potsherds, bronzes and other artifacts, which provided information about the inhabitants of Machu Picchu. Studies of birds and animals in the region produced additional information about living conditions of the Incas, and anthropometric measurements of the Quichua and Machiganga natives revealed anthropological characteristics of the descendants of the Incas. Zoological collections of the expedition included specimens of 80 species of mammals, 400 species of birds, 15-20 species of snakes, and numerous specimens of fish and insects. These zoological specimens were turned over to the United States National Museum, and the expeditions' artifacts and photographs were placed in the Peabody Museum, Yale University.
Bingham planned to continue his explorations in Peru, but in 1917 the National Geographic Society denied his request for funding another expedition. Yet Bingham retained his interest in Peru, and published several more articles and books giving accounts of his experiences and discoveries as director of the Yale Peruvian expeditions.
Anthropology; Archaeology; Incas; Photography; Science; Coropuna (Nudo, Peru); Cuzco (Peru); Lake Parinacochas (Peru); Latin America; Machu Picchu Site (Peru); Peru -- Antiquities; Peru -- Discovery and exploration; Urubamba River (Peru); Vitcos (Peru); Yuracrumiu (Peru); Maps; Photoprints; Scrapbooks; Diaries; Explorers; Anderson, Edwin L.; Barbour, Thomas, 1884-1946; Bestor, Paul, 1882-1962; Bingham, Hiram, 1875-1956; Bowman, Isaiah, 1878-1950; Breckinridge, Henry, 1886-1960; Bryce, James Bryce, Viscount, 1838-1922; Bumstead, Albert H. (Albert Hoit), 1875-1940; Camp, Walter, 1859-1925; Chapman, Frank M. (Frank Michler), 1864-1945; Cook, O. F. (Orator Fuller), 1867-1949; Croke, J. Greenbag, 1840-; Dana, Edward Salisbury, 1849-1935; Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959; Dyar, Harrison G. (Harrison Gray), 1866-1929; Eastman, George, 1854-1932; Eaton, George Francis, 1872-1949; Erdis, Ellwood C.; Erving, William Gage, 1877-1923; Ferris, H. B. (Harry Burr), 1865-1940; Foote, H. W. (Harry Ward), 1875-1942; Ford, David E.; Giesecke, Albert Anthony, 1880-1968; Goddard, Pliny Earle, 1869-1928; Gorgas, William Crawford, 1854-1920; Gregory, Herbert E. (Herbert Ernest), 1869-1952; Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey, 1875-1966; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Hardy, Osgood, 1889-1955; Harkness, Edward Stephen, 1874-1940; Heald, K. C. (Kenneth Conrad), 1888-1971; Heller, Edmund, 1875-1939; Hendriksen, Kai; Higginson, Edwardo; Hilles, Charles Dewey, 1867-1949; Hinckley, F.; Holmes, William Henry, 1874-; Aaron, Harold, 1860-1928; Hrdlička, Aleš, 1869-1943; Lanius, Paul B.; Leguía, Augusto Bernardino, 1863-1932; Little, Joseph P.; Markham, Clements R., Sir (Clements Robert), 1830-1916; Maynard, Clarence F.; Means, Philip Ainsworth, 1892-1944; Meserve, Edwin A.; Miller, Gerrit S. (Gerrit Smith), 1869-1956; Nelson, Luther Townsend, 1882-; Pezet, Federico Alfonso, 1859-1929; Pickering, Edward C. (Edward Charles), 1846-1919; Schuchert, Charles, 1858-1942; Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924; Tucker, Herman L.; Wedemeyer, William Walter, 1863-1913; Westerberg, C. Frederick; Willoughby, Charles Clark, 1857-1943; Abercrombie & Fitch; Eastman Kodak Company; National Geographic Society (U.S.); Yale University -- Faculty
- Administrative records, 1908-1916; Series I; 2' (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of plans for the expedition, press releases and reports, applications, staff contracts, instructions for staff, staff suggestions, letters of introduction, official documents, legal papers, reference material, invitations, programs, supply inventories, timetables and brochures. The material is arranged chronologically by type.
  - Plans for expedition, 1911-1912, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Press releases and reports, 1912, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Applications, 1912, 1914-1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
  - Staff contracts, 1911-1912, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
  - Instructions for staff, 1911-1912, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 14-19)
  - Staff suggestions, 1911, 1914-1915, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letters of introduction, 1911, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letters of introduction, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Official documents and legal papers
    - 1908, 1911-1912, 1914-1915, undated (Box 2, Folder 23-25)
    - Correspondence, 1911-1915 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Permits to remove artifacts from Peru, 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Cabled news of expedition: requests, addresses and messages, 1914-1916 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Circular letters, 1915 January-March (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Reference material
    - Bibliography (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Place names in Peru (Box 2, Folder 31-33)
      General
      See also: Bingham Family Papers, Series V: notecard files
    - Writings about Peru (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Antonio de la Calancha, Chronicle
      - pp. 1-70 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - pp. 71-164 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - (Duplicate), pp. 1-70 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - (Duplicate), pp. 71-164 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - (Excerpts) (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - (Translation), pp. 1-72 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - (Translation), pp. 73-152 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Montesinos, Anales del Peru (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Montesinos, Memorias Antiguas … del Peru (Translation) (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Published articles (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Photography (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Weather observations (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Equipment and scientific instruments (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
    - Charts and tables (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Invitations, calling cards and address lists (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Programs (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Supply inventories, 1911-1912, 1914-1915, undated (Box 4, Folder 53-59)
    - Timetables and brochures (Box 4, Folder 60-63)
- Correspondence, 1909-1925; Series II; 5' (13 boxes)
  General Correspondence consists of letters received by Bingham and the expedition office and copies of outgoing letters. The correspondence is arranged chronologically, from 1909 to 1917.
  Select Correspondence consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence with Eastman Kodak Company, the National Geographic Society, and the Yale University Treasurer's Office, between 1911 and 1917. Bingham's letters received concerning publication of Inca Land are dated from 1921 to 1925. H. B. Ferris' correspondence, 1912-1921, relates in part to his association with the expedition. The Select Correspondence is arranged chronologically within each of these categories.
  - General Correspondence
    - 1909 - 1910 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1911
      - January - March 10, March 12-April 18, April 21-October (Box 5, Folder 2-29)
      - 1911 November-Dec, undated (Box 6, Folder 30-32)
    - 1912
      - January - April 30 (Box 6, Folder 33-54)
      - May - November 30 (Box 7, Folder 55-73)
      - Dec, undated (Box 8, Folder 74-75)
    - 1913
      - January - April 30 (Box 8, Folder 76-96)
      - May - December 31 (Box 9, Folder 97-119)
    - 1914
      - January - September (Box 10, Folder 120-142)
      - October 1 - December (Box 11, Folder 143-146)
    - 1915
      - January 1 - June 30 (Box 11, Folder 147-166)
      - July 1 - December 31, undated (Box 12, Folder 167-180)
    - 1916
      - January 1 - February 29 (Box 12, Folder 181-186)
      - March 1 - Dec, undated (Box 13, Folder 187-204)
    - 1917
      - January - May, December (Box 13, Folder 205-207)
      - Undated (letters) (Box 13, Folder 208)
      - Undated (letter fragments and notes) (Box 13, Folder 209)
  - Select Correspondence
    - Eastman Kodak Company
      - 1911-1912 March - May, 1912 November - December (Box 14, Folder 210-213)
      - 1913
        - January - December (Box 14, Folder 214-221)
      - 1914
        - January-Jul, October - December (Box 14, Folder 222-226)
      - 1915
        - January - Apr, June - December (Box 14, Folder 227-230)
      - 1916 January - February (Box 14, Folder 231)
        - March-December (Box 15, Folder 232-234)
      - 1917 February- May, Oct, December (Box 15, Folder 235-236)
    - National Geographical Society
      - 1912 January - December (Box 15, Folder 237-238)
      - 1913 January - December (Box 15, Folder 239-246)
      - 1914 (Box 15, Folder 247-252)
      - 1915 (Box 15, Folder 253-258)
      - 1916
        - January - December (Box 16, Folder 259-265)
        - 1917, undated (Box 16, Folder 266-267)
    - Yale University, Treasurer's Office
      - 1911 March - Jul, Dec, 1912 March-Dec, 1913 (Box 16, Folder 268-276)
      - 1914
        - January - December (Box 16, Folder 277-282)
      - 1915 January - May, 1915 September - 1916 Jun, Dec, 1917; undated (Box 16, Folder 283-289)
    - Publication of Inca Land
      - 1921 October - 1922 April (Box 17, Folder 290)
      - 1922
        - May - December (Box 17, Folder 291-298)
      - 1923 January - Jun, 1923 August - Dec, 1924-1925 (Box 17, Folder 299-301)
    - Correspondence of H.B. Ferris
      - 1912-1921 (Box 17, Folder 302-303)
- Journals and Notebooks, 1911-1915; Series III; 2' (6 boxes)
  Series III consists of journals and notebooks kept by members of the expeditions. It is arranged chronologically by expedition date, and alphabetically by author for each expedition.
  - 1911
    - Bingham, Hiram
      - Journal, 1911 June-December (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1911 June-August (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Bowman, Isaiah
      - Notebook (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Foote, Harry W.
      - Notebook (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Hendriksen, Kai
      - Notebooks (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
    - Hinckley, F. Journal (1 page, typewritten), 1911 October (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Lanius, Paul B.
      - Journal, 1911 June-September (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1911 June-September (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Tucker, H. L.
      - Journal, 1911 October (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Notebooks (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
  - 1912
    - Bestor, Paul
      - Journal, 1912 June-November (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Bingham, Hiram
      - Journal, 1912 May-November (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Notebook, 1913 August (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Bumstead, Albert H.
      - Journal, 1912 June-September (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Notebook, 1912 September (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Eaton, George F.
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1912 May-December (Box 19, Folder 18)
        See also: accession 2014-M-038, box 1, folder 1 (original handwritten notes).
      - Notes, [1912] (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Erdis, Ellwood C.
      - Journal, 1912 July-November (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1912 July-November (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Hardy, Osgood
      - Journal, 1912 June-December (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1912 June-December (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Heald, Kenneth C.
      - Journal, 1912 May-December (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1912 May-December (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Little, Joseph P.
      - Journal, 1912 June-November (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1912 June-November (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Nelson, Luther T.
      - Journal, 1912 June-December (Box 20, Folder 27)
      - Notebooks (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Stephenson, Robert
      - Journal, 1912 June-December (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - 1914-1915
    - Anderson, Edwin L.
      - Journal, 1914 June-December (Box 20, Folder 30)
      - Journa1-notebook, 1915 April-Jul (Box 20, Folder 31-32)
    - Bingham, Hiram
      - Journal-letters, 1915 April-May (Box 20, Folder 33)
      - Journal-memoranda books, 1915 March-July (Box 20, Folder 34-35)
      - Notebook: general orders, circulars, reference notes (Box 20, Folder 36)
      - Notebook: gazeteer (Box 21, Folder 37)
      - Notebook: archaeology, zoology, botany (Box 21, Folder 38)
      - Notebooks (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Erdis, Ellwood C.
      - Journals, 1914 April-1916 February (Box 21, Folder 40-42)
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1914 April-1916 February (Box 21, Folder 43-44)
    - Ford, David E.
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1915 March-December (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Hardy, Osgood
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1914 May-1915 September (Box 22, Folder 46)
      - Notebook (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Hasbrouck, Joseph J.
      - Journals, 1915 April-November (Box 22, Folder 48-50)
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1915 April-November (Box 22, Folder 51)
      - Notebooks: Ollantaytambo survey (Box 22, Folder 52)
      - Notebooks: Ollantaytambo survey (Box 23, Folder 53)
      - Notebooks (Box 23, Folder 54)
      - Notebook (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - Maynard, Clarence F.
      - Journal (typewritten copy), 1915 April-December (Box 23, Folder 56)
      - Journal (typewritten copy: duplicate), 1915 April-December (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - Means, Philip A.
      - Journals, 1914 July-September (Box 23, Folder 58)
    - Meserve, Edwin A.
      - Journal, 1914 June-October (Box 23, Folder 59)
    - Westerberg, C. Frederick
      - Journals, 1914 April-November (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - Unidentified Notebook: pottery found in caves (Box 23, Folder 61)
- Reports and Articles, 1911-1921; Series IV; 2' (4 boxes)
  Series IV consists of manuscript reports and articles and published articles written by members of the expeditions and other scientific experts. It is arranged chronologically by expedition date, and alphabetically by author for each expedition. Articles based on expedition findings which were not written by staff members are located at the end of the alphabetical sequence for each expedition.
  - 1911
    - Bowman, Isaiah (Box 24, Folder 1)
      See also: box 28, folder 4
    - Erving, William G. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Hendriksen, Kai (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Watkins, Casimir (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Articles based on expedition findings (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
  - 1912
    - Bestor, Paul (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Bumstead, Albert H. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Cook, Orator F. [?] (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Eaton, George F. (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
      See also: box 28, folder 4 See also: box 28, folder 12
    - Ferris, H. B.
      - "Anthropometric Data… Collected by L.T. Nelson, M.D.": draft (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
      - "Anthropometric Data… Collected by L.T. Nelson, M.D.": typed draft (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Research material (Box 25, Folder 15-20)
    - Gregory, Herbert E. (Box 25, Folder 21)
      See also: box 28, folder 12
    - Hardy, Osgood (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Heald, Kenneth C. (Box 25, Folder 23-24)
    - Little, Joseph P. (Box 26, Folder 25-26)
    - Nelson, Luther T. (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Articles based on expedition findings (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - 1913
    - Yale Dominican Expedition (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - 1914-1915
    - List of typewritten copies of staff reports, articles and diaries (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Anderson, Edwin L. (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Bumstead, Albert H. (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Cook, Orator F. and G. Bruce Gilbert (Box 26, Folder 33)
      See also: box 24, folder 9 See also: box 29, folder 22
    - Ferris, H. B.
      - "Anthropological Studies on the Quichua and Machiganga Indians": page proofs (Box 26, Folder 34)
      - "Anthropological Studies on the Quichua and Machiganga Indians": draft (Box 26, Folder 35-36)
      - Research material (Box 26, Folder 37-38)
      - Research material (Box 27, Folder 39-40)
      - Research material collected by David E. Ford (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Ford, David E. (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Hardy, Osgood (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Hardy, Osgood Trip to Puerto Rico, 1913-1914 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Hasbrouck, Joseph J. (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Heller, Edmund (Box 27, Folder 46-47)
    - Maynard, Clarence F. (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Wrigley, Gladys M. (Box 27, Folder 49)
- Writings of Hiram Bingham, 1912-1948; Series V; 1' (3 boxes)
  Series V consists of published articles, manuscripts of articles and speeches, and manuscripts and notes for books about Peru. These writings are arranged chronologically.
  - "Preliminary Report of the Yale Peruvian Expedition", 1912 January (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - "The Ascent of Coropuna": manuscript, 1912 March (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - "Vitcos, the Last Inca Capital", 1912 April (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - "The Discovery of Pre-Historic Human Remains near Cuzco, Peru", 1912 April (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - "Lake Parinacochas and the Composition of Its Water" (co-author, George S. Jamieson), 1912 July (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Address at University of Cuzco: manuscript, 1912 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - "Recent Exploration in the Land of the Incas": abstract of lecture, 1912 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - "Preliminary Report of the Peruvian Expedition of 1912":, Circa 1913 January
    - manuscript (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - notes and rough drafts (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - "In the Wonderland of Peru: the Work Accomplished by the Peruvian Expedition of 1912", 1913 April
    - "The Discovery of Machu Picchu", 1913 April (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - "The Investigation of the Prehistoric Human Remains Found near Cuzco, Peru, in 1911", 1913 July (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - "Exploration in Peru", 1914 March (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - "The Ruins of Espiritu Pampa, Peru", 1914 June (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - "Along the Uncharted Pampaconas", 1914 August (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - "The Pampaconas River", 1914 August (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - "Types of Machu Picchu Pottery", 1915 June (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - "The Inca Peoples and Their Culture": manuscript, 1915 December (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - "Methods Followed in the Field Work of the Peruvian Expeditions": manuscript, 1915 December (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - "Results of Further Studies in the History of Machu Picchu": manuscript and notes, Circa1915 (?) (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - "Evidences of Ancient Symbolism in the Land of the Incas": manuscript, 1916 May (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - "Further Explorations in the Land of the Incas", 1916 May
    - National Geographic Magazine, 1916 May (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - final draft (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - final draft, picture titles (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - preliminary draft, pp. 1-97 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - preliminary draft, pp. 98-200 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - preliminary draft, pp. 201-284 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - notes and drawings (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - notes and partial drafts (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Inca Land, 1922
    - manuscript (part 1) (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - manuscript (part 2) (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - manuscript (part 3) (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - manuscript (part 4) (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - contract, bills, royalty statements, 1922-1923 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - correspondence re: publication of Inca Land, 1921-1925
      See also: box 17, folder 290-301
    - Inca Land reviews, 1922-1923
      See also: box 35, folder 54
  - "Evidences of Symbolism in the Land of the Incas", 1924 January (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - Machu Picchu: A Citadel of the Incas, 1930
    - manuscript (part 1) (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - manuscript (part 2) (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - manuscript, partial draft (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - notes and partial drafts (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - Lost City of the Incas, 1948
    - first edition, corrected copy (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - manuscript, pp. 1-87 (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - manuscript, pp. 88-167 (Box 30, Folder 42)
    - manuscript, pp. 168-259 (Box 30, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 44)
- Photographs, Maps and Scrapbooks, 1911-1923; Series VI; 2' (5 boxes)
  Series VI consists of photographs, glass slides and related materials, maps, newspaper clippings, and scrapbooks. These materials are arranged by type of document.
  Separated Materials
  Landscapes in Peru (glass slides), originally in Box 34, folder 45, were discarded due to condition.
  - Glass slides taken by H.W. Foote
    Conditions Governing Access
    Due to their physical nature, staff supervision is required to use these materials.
    - Peru, expedition staff (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Peru, expedition staff (transporters) (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Peru, Inca ruins (Box 31, Folder 3-5)
    - Peru, landscapes (Box 31, Folder 6-9)
    - Peru, natives (Box 31, Folder 10-12)
    - Peru, buildings (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Peru, animals (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - South America (Box 32, Folder 15-27)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 28-35)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 36-39)
  - Glass negatives: Peruvian crafts (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - Glass negatives: Peruvian crafts and artifacts (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - Glass negatives (Box 33A)
    These materials are restricted pending conservation treatment.
  - Photographs of Quichua Indians taken by David E. Ford, 1915 (Box 34, Folder 42-43)
  - Photographs
    - Pottery and landscapes in Peru (Box 34, Folder 44)
      Some of the images may not be of Peru.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 46)
  - Photograph exhibition catalogs: photographs taken by Peruvian expeditions of, 1911-1915 (Box 34, Folder 47)
  - Photographs: lists of captions and of photographs ordered (Box 34, Folder 48-49)
  - Maps: hand-drawn and printed (Box 34, Folder 50)
  - Newspaper clippings from Peru, in Spanish and in English (Box 34, Folder 51)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Peruvian Expedition, 1911-1913 (Box 35, Folder 52)
      - Additional scrapbook, 1914-1917 (Box 35A, Folder 53)
    - Inca Land reviews, 1922-1923 (Box 35B, Folder 54)
- Financial Records, 1911-1917; Series VII; 2' (5 boxes)
  Series VII consists of general expense papers, expense books, record books, checkbooks and stubs, expense records, work schedule records, time cards, bills and receipts. The materials are arranged chronologically by type.
  - General expenses
    - 1911-1915 (Box 36, Folder 1-3)
  - Expense books
    - Bestor, Bingham, Bumstead, 1912 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Eaton, Gregory, Hardy, 1912 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Heald, Little, Means, 1912 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Nelson, Stephenson and Erdis, 1912 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Anderson, Bingham, Bumstead, 1914-1915 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Erdis, Ford, Hardy, 1914-1915 (Box 37, Folder 9)